{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Consider a system with transfer function G(s) = (s + 4)/ (k s^2 + s + 4). The value of damping ratio will be 0.5 when the value of k is _____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1/2",
        "b": "1/4",
        "c": "8",
        "d": "4"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. The time constant of a first order process with resistance R and capacitance C is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "RC",
        "b": "R+C",
        "c": "R-C",
        "d": "1/RC"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Which of the following controllers has maximum offset ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "P controller",
        "b": "PI controller",
        "c": "PD controller",
        "d": "PID controller"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. The gas temperatures at any two given instants are the same. The process is _____.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Isothermal",
        "b": "Isobaric",
        "c": "Isobaric",
        "d": "Isovolumetric"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. What is the relationship between the steady-state error, gain and the tendency of oscillations when the controller is supposed to be under the proportional action?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Steady-state error increases with an increase in gain and oscillation tendency",
        "b": "Steady-state error decreases with the decrease in gain and oscillation tendency",
		"c": "Steady-state error decreases with an increase in gain and oscillation tendency",
        "d": "Steady-state error increases with the decrease in gain and oscillation tendency"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. The input to a controller is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Sensed Signal",
        "b": "Error Signal",
        "c": "Desired variable value",
        "d": "Signal of fixed amplitude not dependent on desired variable value"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
   
    {
      "question": "7. Proportional band of the controller is expressed as:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Gain",
        "b": "Ratio",
        "c": "Percentage",
        "d": "Range of control variables"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }, 
    
	
	{
      "question": "8. Most thermal processes in process control systems do not involve _____ heat transfer.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Conduction",
        "b": "Radiation",
        "c": "Convection",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "9. In case of a PID controller, the _____ process involved may cause serious noise problems",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Integration",
        "b": "Differentiation",
        "c": "Both of the above",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "10. The use of a lag–lead compensator raises the order of the system by ______ unless cancellation occurs between zero(s) of the lag–lead compensator and pole(s) of the uncompensated open-loop transfer function.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "3",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}